Guide to the Blackout Arts Collective Archive MSS.379
Fales Library and Special Collections
Blackout Arts Collective Archive
1992-2011
2001-2007
Fales Library and Special Collections
Blackout Arts Collective
MSS.379
7.5 Linear Feet (14 boxes)
The Blackout Arts Collective, started in New York City in 1997, is a group of artists, community organizers, students, teachers, professionals, entrepreneurs, and formerly incarcerated individuals working to empower communities of color through the arts, activism and education. This collection consists of their administrative records.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Arrangement
The archivist attempted to respect the original order of the Blackout Arts Collective material and arranged the files into seven series.
Series I: Administrative Files
Series II: Projects
Series III: Financial Files
Series IV: Subject Files
Series V: Media
Oversize Series VI: Posters
Series VII: Data Storage
The contents of each series are described in the scope and content notes at the series level. Within each series, the materials are arranged alphabetically by folder title. Folder titles in brackets indicate that the archivist chose a logical folder title for materials that were not labeled. Dates in brackets indicate that the date shown was an educated guess. Oversize materials were removed from original folders due to size.
Historical Note
Started in New York City in 1997, The Blackout Arts Collective's mission is to empower communities of color through the arts, activism and education. BAC is an ensemble group of artists and community organizers, students and teachers, professionals and entrepreneurs, and formerly incarcerated individuals. "A blackout happens when the power system fails us"*, and BAC seeks to shine light on positive community building efforts, and call out oppressive and discriminatory practices that work in opposition to such efforts. BAC uses arts and education to raise awareness and spark action related to the most important political, social and cultural issues facing communities of color, including: incarceration and police brutality, equity in education, domestic violence, militarism and counter-terrorism, voter registration and local economic development.
From the late 1990s through the mid 2000s, BAC worked locally, and on a national scale, hosting monthly arts showcases at some of New York City's notable performance venues and facilitating political and arts education workshops for youth. Blackout's signature program was a touring performance and organizing project entitled "Lyrics on Lockdown: Slamming the Prison Industrial Complex", which visited adult prisons, youth detention facilities, community centers and summer camps around the United States.** The success of the four Lyrics on Lockdown tour summers (2001 - 2004) spawned Blackout chapters in cities from coast-to-coast, with a strong presence in Boston, Philadelphia, New Haven, Houston, New Orleans and Washington, DC, where local organizers developed their own unique programming.
The organization still exists, but has since evolved into a national network of artists, scholars and advocates who collaborate on select projects, still utilizing art to push for progressive social change.***
*http://socialjustice.ccnmtl.columbia.edu/index.php/BlackOut_Arts_Collective **http://www.idealist.org/view/nonprofit/wC3Sj4nWMH8d/ ***Conversation with Nigel Greaves, July 17, 2014.
Provenance
The Blackout Arts Collective Archive was donated to NYU's Fales Library & Special Collections in 2013 by members of the Collective.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual and born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of materials related to and produced by the administration of an independent arts organization including ephemera, tour schedules and contracts, grants administration material, financial records, resumes, photographs and negatives, membership forms, material generated in the planning stages of projects, organizational publications, and a small collection of social justice publications by other organizations, among other material.
African American political activists; Community activists.; Résumés (personnel records); Financial records; Juvenile detention.; Social justice.; Posters.; Grant proposals.; Correspondence.; Race |x Political aspects.; Political activists.; Social conditions -- Art -- United States -- 20th century.; Newsletters.; Art -- Political aspects.; Prison reformers.; Art |x Management.; Elections -- United States.; Art and society.; Police brutality.; Bain, Bryonn
- Series I: Administrative Files
  Scope and Content
  This series contains documents related to the daily functioning of a non-profit organization including planning documents, membership files, resumes, ephemera, and other material. These files are general and not linked to particular projects.
  - Artist Resumes, [2004] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - BAC - Archives, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - BAC - Old, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - BAC - Opportunity, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - BAC - Peer Organizations, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - BAC - Strategic Planning Consultants, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative and Financial Papers] (1 of 2), 2001-2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative and Financial Papers] (2 of 2), 2001-2006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative Files], 2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative Files], 2003 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative Files] (1 of 9), Undated, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative Files] (2 of 9), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative Files] (3 of 9), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative Files] (4 of 9), 2003 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative Files] (5 of 9), 2003 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative Files] (6 of 9), 2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative Files] (7 of 9), 2003 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative Files] (8 of 9), 2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative Files] (9 of 9), 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - [Blackout Arts Administrative Files; Humanities Council of Washington D.C.], 2003 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - [Blackout Arts Collective: Free! Education 2005] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - [Blackout Arts Collective Miscellaneous Evaluation Forms], [2004] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - [Blackout Arts Collective: Miscellaneous Papers], [1999] (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - [Blackout Arts Collective National Retreat], 2003 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - [Blackout Arts: Creating Agency Business Plan], 2006 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - [Blackout Arts D.C., Community Publications, Correspondence] (1 of 2), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - [Blackout Arts D.C., Community Publications, Correspondence] (2 of 2), 2004 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - [Blackout Arts Education Justice Campaign and Education Reform Resources, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - [Blackout Arts Ephemera], 2001-2006 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - [Blackout Arts Ephemera], Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - [Blackout Arts Notepad], Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - [Blackout Arts Press Release], Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - [Blackout Ephemera], 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - [Blackout Ephemera], 2002-2007 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - [Blackout Ephemera], Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - [Blackout- Piper], Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - [Blackout Photographs and Negatives] (1 of 2), Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - [Blackout Photographs and Negatives] (2 of 2), Undated, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bios/Resumes (BAC) BAC Members, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bulletin Board Info - Pictures from Wall, 1998-2007 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Conference on PIC Panels - Workshops Columbia Criminal Justice, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Development Materials (Proposals and Plans), Projects, T-Shirts, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Events, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Ford Foundation, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - [Membership Forms; Atlanta] (1 of 6), 2005 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - [Membership Forms; Houston] (2 of 6), 2005 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - [Membership; New Haven] (3 of 6), 2005 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - [Membership Forms; New Orleans] (4 of 6), 2005 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - [Membership Forms; New York] (5 of 6), 2005 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - [Membership Forms; Washington D.C.] (6 of 6), [2005] (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - [Miscellaneous], [2007], undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - New York Foundation for the Arts: Blackout Arts Collective, 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Nigel D. Greaves, 2003-2005 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - [Notepads], [2006] (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - [Notepads], Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - [Notepads], Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - [Notepads], Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - OSI - Planning Grant (1 of 2), 2001 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - OSI - Planning Grant (2 of 2), 2001 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Prison Correspondence, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - PR Materials, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - TA Workshop Evals 2005 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - [Teaching Artist Connections], 2004 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Tides Foundation, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series II: Projects
  This series contains materials generated in the process of administering specific projects including Lyrics on Lockdown. The material includes tour schedules, ephemera, correspondence, and financial information.
  - [Art Start], Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - [Bryonn Bain "A Black Man's Bill of Rights" Research Files], [2000] (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Bryonn Bain: Problem Child, the Prophet Returns [1 of 6], 2003 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Bryonn Bain: Problem Child, the Prophet Returns [2 of 6], 2003 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bryonn Bain: Problem Child, the Prophet Returns [3 of 6], 2001 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bryonn Bain: Problem Child, the Prophet Returns [4 of 6], 2001-2004 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Bryonn Bain: Problem Child, the Prophet Returns [5 of 6], 2001-2004 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bryonn Bain: Problem Child, the Prophet Returns [6 of 6], 2003 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - [Bryonn Bain:] Problem Child Tour '05, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - [Guestbook], Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - [i got somethin' to say...2003] (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - [In Her Memory], 2006 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Lyrical Liberation 2004 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - [Lyrical Liberation Schedule], 2004 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - [Lyrical Liberation:] Blackout Arts Collective, "Lyrical Liberation: Envisioning a Prison Free Future", First Annual Youth Justice Forum: August 20-22, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lyrical Liberation: First Annual Youth Justice Forum August 20-22, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Lyrics on Lockdown, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Lyrics on Lockdown 2001 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Lyrics on Lockdown 2003 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Lyrics on Lockdown 2004 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown 2007 at Rikers] (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Lyrics on Lockdown 2002 Papers - Evals Blank (1 of 7) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Lyrics on Lockdown 2002 Papers - Evals Completed (2 of 7) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Lyrics on Lockdown 2002 Papers - Archives and Contracts (3 of 7) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Lyrics on Lockdown 2002 Papers - [Poetry] (4 of 7) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Lyrics on Lockdown 2002 Papers - [Itineraries] (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Lyrics on Lockdown 2002 Papers - [Community Fliers] (6 of 7) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Lyrics on Lockdown 2002 Papers - [Community Fliers] (7 of 7 ) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown 2004 Papers - Front Insert] (1 of 7) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown 2004 Papers - Budgets/Espenses] (2 of 7) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown 2004 Papers - Training Camp] (3 of 7) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown 2004 Papers - Resources and Collaborations] (4 of 7) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown 2004 Papers - Program Materials] (5 of 7) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown 2004 Papers - Publications] (6 of 7) (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown 2004 Papers - Back Insert] (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown] '01 Reimbursement Processed, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown:] Alternative Incarceration Center, Bridgeport, CT, Undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown: Articles on Prison], 2000-2004 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown: Articles on Prison] (2 of 4), 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown: Articles on Prison] (3 of 4), 2003-2004
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown: Articles on Prison] (4 of 4), 2003-2004 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown:] BAC Finance...to be processed: LOL 2002 - Expenses TKM Charges (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown:] BAC Finance...to be processed: LOL Tour Receipts (from Laurent) 2002 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown: Blackout Arts - Photographs, Responses, and Finance/Receipts] (1 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown: Blackout Arts-Photographs, Responses, and Finance/Receipts] (2 of 3), 2005 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown: Blackout Arts-Photographs, Responses, and Finance/Receipts], 2001 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown: Clearance Forms], 2007 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown:] Commitments, [2005] (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown Critical Literacy Through Hip-Hop and Spoken Word], 2006 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown:] Evaluation Forms - LOL '04, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown: My Lyrics Will Not be on Lockdown: Youth Envisioning a Prison-Free Future], [2005] (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown:] OSI, 2002-2003 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown:] Prep for LOL Tour, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown:] Retreat 2005 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown Workshops: Family/Community] (1 of 2), 2007 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown Workshops: Family/Community] (2 of 2), 2007 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown Workshops: Identity], 2007 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown Workshops, Police], 2007 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown:] Youth Voices on Lockdown, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - [A Performative Critique of Democracy by Blackout Arts Collective, NYU Review of Law & Social Change], 2001-2002 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - [She Speaks for Freedom!, Blackout Arts Collective Presents], Undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - What It Iz?, 2004 (Box 9, Folder data_value_missing_2f7a77de39e3c514daa9567dd2eb4240)
  - What It Iz 2006, 2005-2006 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - [What It Iz:] Assata, [2004] (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - [What It Iz:] Callback Sides, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - What It Iz Evals 2006 Completed (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - What It Iz - Judge/OBC, Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - [What It Iz - Sides] Dorothy, Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - What It Iz - Sides [Evilese], Undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - What It Iz Side Eye Am, Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - What It Iz - Side Platinum, Undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - What It Iz Side Smooth, Undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - What It Iz: The Spokenwordical, [2003] (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - [What It Iz: The Spokenwordical Press Materials], 2006 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Youth Justice Pub '04-'05, 2004-2005 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Youth Justice Publication: 2005 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Series III: Financial Files
  This series contains materials related to the financial functioning of the organization including grant proposals and documentation.
  - BAC Finance...to be Processed, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Benefit-Checks, 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - [Blackout Arts Financial Papers], 2005-2010 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - [Blackout Arts Financial Report and Papers], 2004, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Finance-2003 Retreat (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Finance-New York Foundation for the Arts, [2000-2001] (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Finance-New York Foundation for the Arts, [2003] (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - New York Foundation for the Arts Correspondence, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - [New York Foundation for the Arts Financial Forms], 1992-2000 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - [New York Foundation for the Arts Financial Papers] (1 of 2), 2007-2010 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - [New York Foundation for the Arts Financial Papers] (2 of 2), 2008-2009 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - [New York Foundation for the Arts Fiscal Correspondence: Blackout Arts Development and Financial Transactions], 2001-2007 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Series IV: Subject Files
  This series contains material generated by other organizations and collected by BAC in the service of their work, including ephemera, publications, conference guides, and other material.
  - Arts Organization Fliers, 2005-2006 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - The Center for Young Women's Development, Undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Coalition for Women Prisoners, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - [Community/Social Justice Publications], 2003-2011 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - [Community Organization Ephemera], Undated (Box 10, Folder 16a)
  - [Connecting Communities: Generations Against Gentrification], 2005 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - [Correctional Association of New York Coalition for Women Prisoners Papers: Prisoner Correspondence], 2004-2007 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Critical Resistance, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - [The Foundation Center-Washington DC Papers] (1 of 2), 2003
  - [The Foundation Center-Washington DC Papers] (2 of 2), 2002 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Generation Engage, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - H2A: Facilitating, Fostering, and Preserving Hip-Hop Culture, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Homes for the Homeless-Folder, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Incite Women of Color, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Institute for Urban Education, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Intersection IV: Re/Generations, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - [Miscellaneous Papers on Incarceration], 2004-2006 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - No "Give Up On Youth" Laws-Take Urgent Action Now!, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - North Star-2003 Activist Forum (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - [Outside Publications: Community Publications], 2004 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - [Outside Publications: Non-Profit Arts Organizations], 2006 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - [Outside Publications: Non-Profit Arts Organizations] (2 of 3), 2005-2006 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - [Outside Publications: Non-Profit Arts Organizations], 2005-2006 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - [Outside Publications: Non-Profit Managment and Development] (1 of 2), 2000-2007 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - [Outside Publications: Non-Profit Managment and Development] (2 of 2), 2005-2007 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - [Outside Publications: "The Jones Family Express" by Javaka Steptoe, Undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - [Outside Publications Political Newsletters], 2005-2006 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - [Outside Publications: Political Newsletters] (2 of 2), 2004-2006 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - [Outside Publications: Prisoner Publications], 2004-2005 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - [Outside Publications: Public Policy] (1 of 3), 2004-2005 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - [Outside Publications: Public Policy] (2 of 3), 2001 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - [Outside Publications: Public Policy] (3 of 3), 2001-2006 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - [Outside Publications: Third World Newsreel Catalogue], 2003 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - [Outside Publications: Youth Organizing], 2003-2006 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - [Papers from Community Organizations], [2006-2008] (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - [Prison Moratorium Project], 2004-2006 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - PTO Conference 2006 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Series V: Media
  This series contains audiovisual material generated by Blackout Arts.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Untitled DVD, undated; ID: 379.0001 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0001)
    Currently unavailable until duplication occurs.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Original format: DVD-R
  - The Policing Art, undated; ID: 379.0002 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0002)
    Producer/Director: Ashley Alexis McFarlene
    Category: Documentary, Under the Influence, Adult, Short
    Original format: DVD
    Duration: 9 minutes
  - Reading Between the Rhymes, undated; ID: 379.0003 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0003)
    Produced & Directed by Keith Morikawa.
  - Freedom or Everybody Dies by Akintola Harif, undated; ID: 379.0004 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0004)
  - Jahnbaby, undated; ID: 379.0005 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0005)
  - Sparlha Swa, Doing My Thing, undated; ID: 379.0006 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0006)
  - Akintola Hanif, Press Materials, undated; ID: 379.0007 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0007)
    Currently unavailable.
    Original Format: CD-R
  - Immortals 982, undated; ID: 379.0008 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0008)
  - What It Iz Kit, undated; ID: 379.0009 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0009)
  - What It Iz CD, undated; ID: 379.0010 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0010)
    Original format: CD-R
  - Untitled, undated; ID: 379.0011 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0011)
  - What It Iz, undated; ID: 379.0012 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0012)
  - Ty, 6 Songs, undated; ID: 379.0013 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0013)
  - What It Iz Sound Design Backup, January 2, 2005; ID: 379.0014 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0014)
    Music by: H. Nalidah
  - Mental Vision, Black Moses: The Vision, undated; ID: 379.0015 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0015)
    Original format: CD
    Track List: 1. Intro/ Black Moses 2. Follow Me 3. Make Room 4. Ice Cream 5. Move (Get It Poppin) 6. Take It There
    Producers: Zimm, Marko Polo, Tha Original, and Clear Vision
  - What It Iz, Master, undated; ID: 379.0016 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0016)
    Note on original disc: Not In Order
  - What It Iz, 9 Trax, undated; ID: 379.0017 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0017)
  - Untitled, undated; ID: 379.0018 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0018)
    Track List: 1. Thaideology 2. Innocent or Guilty 3. We Gotta Push Thru The Struggle
  - Bares Hammond, "Best Of", undated; ID: 379.0019 (Box 15, Media ID: 379.0019)
- Series VII: Data Storage, Undated
  This series contains three 3.5 inch floppy disks.
  Born-digital materials have not been preserved and are not available to researchers.
  - Blackout, Undated (Box 15, Item ID: 379.3.0001)
  - Blackout-DB, Undated (Box 15, Item ID: 379.3.0002)
  - Lyrics on Lockdown, Nigel, Undated (Box 15, Item 379.3.0003)
- Oversize Series VI: Posters, 2003-2006
  This series contains posters and flyers generated by BAC as advertisements for their events.
  - [Blackout Arts Collective -- Posters, General], Undated (Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 15)
  - [Bryonn Bain -- Underground Speakeasy], 2003 (Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 16)
  - [Lyrics on Lockdown -- Posters], 2003-2005 (Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 17)
  - [Posters, Flyers -- Outside Organizations], 2006, Undated (Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 18)
  - [What It Iz -- Posters], Undated (Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 19)
  - [Incite Women of Color--Posters], 2005 (Folder 18)